Guide to the Ruth D. Cruikshank papers 1977.429
Brooklyn Historical Society
Ruth D. Cruikshank papers
1863-1947
Brooklyn Historical Society
Decker, Reuben S.
Decker, Sarah A.
Cruikshank, Ruth D.
1977.429
0.25 Linear Feet in one box and one flat file folder.
This collection contains various typed and handwritten notes and news clippings on Brooklyn history compiled by Brooklyn resident Ruth D. Cruikshank (b. 1892) and organized by subject matter, as well as materials related to the Decker family of Brooklyn.
Conditions Governing Access
The folder of original "History notes" is restricted due to its fragile condition. The provided photocopies should be used instead.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Gift of Ruth D. Cruikshank, 1965.
Arrangement
The materials are arranged into folders by subject matter.
Biographical note
Reuben S. Decker (1830-1911) was partners with Hamilton Weed in the Capitoline Grounds, which were located on Decker's land, once the estate of the prominent Lefferts family of Brooklyn. One of Decker's daughters was Laura Cruikshank, who may have been Ruth D. Cruikshank's mother.
Physical Characteristics and Technical Requirements
Due to the fragile nature of the originals, researchers should use the phocopied "History notes" whenever possible.
Scope and Contents
This collection contains various typed and handwritten notes and news clippings on Brooklyn history compiled by Brooklyn resident Ruth D. Cruikshank (b. 1892) and organized by subject matter. Subjects include banks, mayors, the military, transportation, recreation, prominent Brooklyn citizens and organizations, the Capitoline Grounds on Bedford Avenue, the neighborhood of East New York, and the East Reformed Presbyterian Church, among others. Also included are materials relating to Reuben S. and Sarah A. Decker. Items pertaining to the Decker family include a journal, legal papers from a dispute between the Decker and Brevoort families, receipts, tax bills, and certificates. The collection spans the period 1863 to 1947.
Brooklyn (New York, N.Y.) -- Intellectual life; Recreation |z New York (State) |z Kings County; Clubs -- New York (State) -- Kings County; East New York (New York, N.Y.); Brooklyn (New York, N.Y.) -- History, Military; Capitoline Grounds (Brooklyn, New York, N.Y.); Brooklyn (New York, N.Y.) -- Social life and customs; Transportation -- New York (State) -- Kings County; Mayors |z New York (State) |z Kings County; Brooklyn (New York, N.Y.) -- History; Banks and banking |z New York (State) |z Kings County; Brooklyn (New York, N.Y.) -- Politics and government; East Reformed Presbyterian Church (Brooklyn, New York, N.Y.); Decker, Reuben S.; Decker, Sarah A.; Decker family
- History notes by topic - originals, undated (Box 1, Folder 1)
  Conditions Governing Access
  This folder is restricted due to the fragility of the documents.
  Physical Characteristics and Technical Requirements
  Researchers should use the provided photocopies for access.
- History notes by topic - photocopies, undated (Box 1, Folder 2)
  Scope and Contents
  Topics in alphabetical order: Academy of Music, Advertisements, Autograph album, Banks, Brooklyn Bridge, Brooklyn Heights, Brooklyn Institute, Brooklyn Theatre victims at Greenwood, Buildings, Columbia Heights, Coney Island, Draft Riots, East River ice, Fires, Friends (Society of), Friends Cemetery, Gas Lighting, Greenwood Cemetery, Irishtown, Judges, Manhattan Beach, Mayors, Monuments, Monument to Lafayette, Orchards, Otton family, Plymouth [Church], Politicians, Ponds, Pratt Institute, Pumps, Revolutionary War, Rollerskating, Sanitary Fair, Schools, Singers, St. John's Church (Fort Hamilton), Streets, Telephones, Temperance, Theatres, Transportation, Waterfront, Williamsburg, Yacht Clubs and Yachting. The subject topics are followed by individuals listed by surname: Abbott, Dr. Lyman; Beecher, Henry Ward; Conway, Lillian; Cragin, Mrs. E.S.; Fancher, Mollie; Kidd, Captain; MacFarland, Daniel; McLean, Andrew; MacMonnies, Frederick; Mosher, Dr. Eliza; Storrs, Rev. Richard Salter; Stranahan, J.S.T.; Talmage, T. De Witt.
- The Capitoline Grounds documents and clippings, circa 1888-1947 (Box 1, Folder 3, Folder Flat File)
  One oversize survey of the Grounds and several blocks surrounding them, with points of interest marked, is stored in a flat file.
- East New York history notes, undated (Box 1, Folder 4)
- East Reformed Presbyterian Church document and notes, undated (Box 1, Folder 5)
  One circa 19th century document with specifications of the mason work to be done at the church and three pages with Cruikshank's research notes.
- "Staging Area - Brooklyn," pp. 11-64, December 9, 1945 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  A publication of the Brooklyn Daily Eagle about Brooklyn's role in WWII.
- Research notes, undated (Box 1, Folder 7)
  Topics include Brooklyn Free Library, Navy Yard, Tom Paine, Henry Ward Beecher, Long Island Bank, R.D. Alliger, and the Brooklyn Theatre fire.
- Decker family papers and clippings, 1863-1927 (Box 1, Folder 8)
- R.S. Decker diary, 1876 (Box 1, Folder 9)
- Journal, undated (Box 1, Folder 10)
- Account book and scrapbook, undated (Box 1, Folder 11)
- Herkimer Street and Prescott Place survey, 1885 (Box 1, Folder 12)